archanaskitchen.com 2015-05-12

# Privacy Policy | Simple and Easy to Make Healthy Vegetarian Recipes and Videos

PRIVACY POLICY

We, Archana’s Online Media & Publishing Services LLP( Archana’s Kitchen), the creators of this Privacy Policy ensure our firm commitment to your privacy vis-à-vis the protection of your priceless information. In order to endow you with our uninterrupted use of services, we may collect and, in some circumstances, disclose information about you. To enhance better protection of your privacy we provide this notice explaining our information practices and the choices you can make about the way your information is collected and used.

This privacy policy should be read in accordance with any agreement you have with Archana’s Kitchen and [www.archanaskitchen.com](http://www.archanaskitchen.com/)  including our Terms of Service. If you have any questions or concerns regarding this privacy policy, you should contact us at [info@archanaskitchen.com](mailto:info@archanaskitchen.com).

1\. OVERVIEW

We commit to respecting your online privacy data. We further recognize your need for appropriate protection and management of any personally identifiable information ("Personal Information") you share with us. Information that is considered personal about you by us includes, but is not limited to, your name, address, email address or other contact information.

In general the website DOES NOT require the user to register on the website. All information on the website is available to everyone. However, we collect non personally identify-able data such as ip address and other logs which may be used for analysing traffic and trends.

2\. NOTIFICATION OF MODIFICATION AND CHANGES TO THE T&C AND THE PRIVACY POLICY

We reserve the right to change the Terms and Privacy Policy from time to time as seen fit, without any intimation to you, and your continued use of the site will signify your acceptance of any amendment to these terms. 

You are therefore advised to re-read the Terms of Service on a regular basis. Should it be that you do not accept any of the modifications or amendments to the Terms, you may terminate your use of this website immediately.

3\. INFORMATION WE COLLECT

Information directly obtained from you:

In general the website DOES NOT require the user to register on the website. The site may site require you to give us contact information (like name, address, e-mail and telephone number) for the purposes of leaving comments, submiting content, participating in contest, seeking quotes and information on products from affiliates and partners and to subscribe to its newsletter. 

Any communication between you and the website, along with queries and posts on our website are also included in this. Certain information, such as your name, e-mail addresses, is collected in order to, among other things; verify your identity, use as account numbers in our record system and to provide information for the leads generated.

Information collected indirectly: 

Certain information about you is collected automatically when you visit our website. This includes your IP address, broswer type and operating system, your immediate internet history, information collected through cookies (more information on this below), etc. 

We may also obtain information relating to you from third party sources such as social networking websites, databases, online marketing firms, etc. This information includes your username and other information on those sites,  demographic data like age, gender and other interests;  viewing data and advertisement interaction.

4\. COOKIES

We use data collection devices such as "cookies" on certain pages of our Websites. "Cookies" are small files sited on your hard drive that assist us in providing customized services. We also offer certain features that are only available through the use of a "cookie". Cookies can also help us provide information, which is targeted to your interests. Cookies may be used to identify logged in or registered users.

The site uses a of third party vendors for advertisements and affiliate programs on the website. These advertisers and affiliates may assign their own cookies via the user's browsers and we do not have any control over that.

Third party vendors including [www.google.com](http://www.google.com/) (“Google”) may use cookies to serve ads based on your visits to this Website. You may visit the website of the third party and choose to opt out of the use of cookies for interest-based advertising, if the third party offers such an option. You may choose to opt-out of the DoubleClick cookie that Google and its partners use for interest-based advertising by visiting [Ads Settings](http://www.google.com/ads/preferences/). (Alternatively, you may choose to opt out of a third-party vendor's use of cookies for interest based advertising by visiting [aboutads.info](http://www.aboutads.info/).)

The website also has enabled the Google Analytics Advertising features, which allows Google to collect data about users on our website via Google advertising cookies and anonymous identifiers, in addition to standard Google Analytics data. You may choose to opt out of this by downloading and installing the Google Analytics opt-out add-on here [https://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout/](https://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout/). 

5\. USE OF YOUR INFORMATION

Your contact information is also used to contact you when necessary. We use your IP address to help diagnose problems with our server, and to administer our Website. Your IP address is also used to help identify you and to gather broad demographic information. Finally, we may use your IP address to help protect our partners and ourselves from fraud. We will continue to enhance our security procedures as new technology becomes available. We will transfer information about you if we are acquired by or merged with another company. In this event, we will notify you by email or by putting a prominent notice on the site before information about you is transferred and becomes subject to a different privacy policy.

We may also share your contact information with some of our partners including certain kitchen equipment dealer.  You consent to this sharing of information and being contacted by our partners by continued use of this website. 

We may release your personal information to a third-party in order comply with a Court Order or other similar legal procedure, or when we believe in good faith that such disclosure is necessary to comply with the law; prevent imminent physical harm or financial loss; or investigate or take action regarding illegal activities, suspected fraud, or violations of Our Terms of Use. We may disclose personally identifiable information to parties in compliance with our Copyright Policy as mentioned in the Terms of Use as we, in our sole discretion, believe necessary or appropriate in connection with an investigation of fraud, intellectual property infringement, piracy, or other unlawful activity. In such events, We may disclose name, address, country, phone number, email address and company name.

6\. EXTERNAL LINKS ON THE WEBSITE

The Website may include hyperlinks to other web sites or content or resources. We have no control over any websites or resources, which are provided by companies or persons other than us. We also display advertisements on the Site, which are often targeted based on the information we collect about you.  Please note that information collected by third party advertisers is not governed by this policy. 

You acknowledge and agree that we are not responsible for the availability of any such external sites or resources, and do not endorse any advertising, products or other materials available on or from such websites or resources.

You acknowledge and agree that We are not liable for any loss or damage which may be incurred by you as a result of the availability of those external sites or resources, or as a result of any reliance placed by you on the completeness, accuracy or existence of any advertising, products or other materials on, or available from, such websites or resources. These third-party service providers and Third-Party Sites may have their own privacy policies governing the storage and retention of your personal information that you may be subject to. We recommend that when you enter a Third-Party Site, you review the Third Party Site’s privacy policy as it relates to safeguarding your personal information. We use third-party advertising companies to serve ads when you visit the Website.

7\. CONFIDENTIALITY

You further acknowledge that the Website may contain information which is designated confidential by us and that you shall not disclose such information without our prior written consent.

Your information is regarded as confidential and therefore will not be divulged to any third party, unless if legally required to do so to the appropriate authorities. 

We will not sell, share, or rent your personal information to any third party or use your e-mail address for unsolicited mail. Any emails sent by us will only be in connection with the provision of agreed services and products.

8\. DISCLOSURE OF YOUR INFORMATION

Due to the existing regulatory environment, we cannot ensure that all of your private communications and other personally identifiable information will never be disclosed in ways not otherwise described in this Privacy Policy. By way of example (without limiting and foregoing), we may be forced to disclose information to the government, law enforcement agencies or third parties. Under certain circumstances, third parties may unlawfully intercept or access transmissions or private communications, or members may abuse or misuse your information that they collect from our Website. Therefore, although we use industry standard practices to protect your privacy, we do not promise, and you should not expect, that your personally identifiable information or private communications would always remain private.

As a matter of policy, we do not sell or rent any personally identifiable information about you to any third party. However, the following describes some of the ways that your personally identifiable information may be disclosed.

8.1External Service Providers: There may be a number of services offered by external service providers that help you use our Websites. If you choose to use these optional services, and in the course of doing so, disclose information to the external service providers, and/or grant them permission to collect information about you, then their use of your information is governed by their private policy.

8.2Other Corporate Entities: We share much of our data, including personally identifiable information about you, with our parent and/or subsidiaries that are committed to serving your online needs and related services, throughout the world. Such data will be shared for the sole purpose of enhancing your browsing experience. To the extent that these entities have access to your information, they will treat it at least as protectively as they treat information they obtain from their other members. It is possible that We and/or its subsidiaries, or any combination of such, could merge with or be acquired by another business entity. Should such a combination occur, you should expect that we would share some or all of your information in order to continue to provide the service. You will receive notice of such event (to the extent that it occurs).

8.3Law and Order: We cooperate with law enforcement inquiries, as well as other third parties to enforce laws, such as: intellectual property rights, fraud and other rights. We can (and you authorize us to) disclose any information about you to law enforcement and other government officials as we, in our sole discretion, believe necessary or appropriate, in connection with an investigation of fraud, intellectual property infringements, or other activity that is illegal or may expose us or you to legal liability.

9\. OTHER INFORMATION COLLECTORS

Except as otherwise expressly included in this Privacy Policy, this document only addresses the use and disclosure of information we collect from you. To the extent that you disclose your information to other parties, whether they are on our Websites or on other sites throughout the Internet, different rules may apply to their use or disclosure of the information you disclose to them. To the extent that we use third party advertisers, they adhere to their own privacy policies. Since we do not control the privacy policies of the third parties, you are subject to ask questions before you disclose your personal information to others.

10\. SECURITY

We treat data as an asset that must be protected against loss and unauthorized access. We employ many different security techniques to protect such data from unauthorized access by members inside and outside the company. We follow generally accepted industry standards to protect the personal information submitted to us, when we receive it. However, "perfect security" does not exist on the Internet. You therefore agree that any security breaches beyond the control of our standard security procedures are at your sole risk and discretion.

11\. DISCLAIMER

We cannot ensure that all of your private communications and other personal information (including sensitive information like credit card information and bank account number) will never be disclosed in ways not otherwise described in this Privacy Policy. Therefore, although we are committed to protecting your privacy, we do not promise, and you should not expect, that your personal information will always remain private. As a user of the Site, you understand and agree that you assume all responsibility and risk for your use of the Site, the internet generally, and the documents you post or access and for your conduct on and off the Site.

12\. QUESTIONS AND SUGGESTIONS

If you have questions about this privacy policy, please send an email to [info@archanaskitchen.com](mailto:info@archanaskitchen.com)
